准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
德克萨斯
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
插曲客串
早安  裤头村
Good morning, Bikini Bottom
多美好的一天啊
What a beautiful day
不知道派大星在不在家
I wonder if Patrick's at home
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hiya, SpongeBob
你在干嘛
Watcha doing?
到珊迪家去
Going over to Sandy's place
这什么
What's this?
这玩意看着不像是珊迪家
This doesn't look like Sandy's place
你们先别急
Don't lose your barnacles, boys
弄好了
There it is
这是什么
What is it?
看不出来吗
Can't you see?
是德克萨斯
It's Texas
德克萨斯
"Texas"?
啥叫德克萨斯
What's a Texas?
现在就只是个念想了
It's nothing but a memory now
那好吧
All right, then
来做你的树屋
Let's make one of your tree dome
其实  我突然就
Y-You know, all of a sudden
不想堆沙堡了  海绵宝宝
l don't feel much like sandcastles, SpongeBob
等会再见吧
I'll see y'all later
珊迪
Sandy
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我现在没心情玩空手道
l'm just not feeling up to karate right now
这我懂
I get it
没心情玩空手道是吧
"Not feeling up to karate," huh?
随你怎么说  珊迪
Whatever you say, Sandy
我可真希望珊迪没从背后偷袭我
Boy, I hope Sandy doesn't attack me from behind
珊迪
Sandy?
来冲浪了  珊迪
Surf's up, Sandy
不用了
No thanks
捉水母最棒了
Boy, there's nothing like going jellyfishing
珊迪你看  我们捉到一只了
Look, Sandy, we caught one
海绵宝宝我跟你说
Listen, SpongeBob
现在我没心情堆沙堡
right now, I don't want to build sandcastles
玩空手道  还有吃水母
play karate or eat jellyfish
我们不会吃水母的
We don't eat 'em
我们会放水母走
We let 'em go
飞吧  小家伙
Fly away, little critter
去吧  回到属于你的地方去吧
Go on, go back home where you belong
去吧  回到你家人和朋友身边去吧
Run along, back to your family and friends
它们一定很想念你
I know they miss you
你也一定很想念它们
as much as you miss them
趁它们没落下你  尽快回去吧
Hurry, before they forget you and leave you behind
[ 苏格兰民歌《可爱的家》(Home Sweet Home) ]
别忘了
Remember
我的家庭真可爱
There's no place like home
珊迪  你到底是在哭什么
Sandy, what the heck are you crying about?
我没哭  只是头盔漏水了而已
l ain't cryin', my helmet just sprung a leak
珊迪
Sandy
我应该只是有一点想家了
I guess I'm just feeling a little homesick
想家是吧
Homesick, huh?
就快到了
Almost there
真是的  海绵宝宝
Dad-gum it, SpongeBob
这是搞什么
what is it?
哒哒哒
Da, ta-dah
欢迎回家  珊迪
Welcome home, Sandy
珊迪
Sandy?
走开
Go away
我想不通  派大星
I don't get it, Patrick
珊迪这是怎么了
What's wrong with Sandy?
可能只有松鼠才懂吧
Maybe it's just a squirrel thing
愿我回到德克萨斯
Wish I was back in Texas
大海不是松鼠的家
The ocean's no place for a squirrel
愿回德克萨斯
Wish I was in Texas
世上最美的地方
Prettiest place in the world
哦不
Oh, no
我想在我内心深处
I guess a-deep in my heart
我将永远是个德克萨斯女孩
I'll always be a Texas girl
我想要回家
I want to go ho-o-o-o-ome
家
Ho-ome
派大星  你听一下
Hey, Patrick, listen to that
快弄下去
Get 'em off me
派大星
Patrick
你听
Listen
听见没
hear that?
是珊迪
It's Sandy
想在德克萨斯醒来
I want to wake up in Texas
我怀念那开阔天空
I miss those wide-open skies
怀念我广阔田野
I miss my 20 acres
烤肉和山核桃派
Barbecues and pecan pies
为什么
Oh, why
距离德州千万里
When I'm so far from you, Texas
我仅能黯然神伤
All I can do is cry
蟹堡王
我想要回家
I want to go ho-o-o-ome
你觉得她是不是知道松饼人之歌啊
Do you think she knows the muffin man song?
派大星  她是发自内心唱出来的
Patrick, she sang that song from her heart
她真的很想念德克萨斯
She really misses Texas
那咱就去弄点德克萨斯过来
Well, let's go get some Texas and bring it down here
派大星  不能
Patrick, you can't
就是这样
That's it
派大星  你的天分发功了
Patrick, your genius is showing
[ genius（天分）与 genital（私处）谐音 ]
哪儿了
Where?
蟹堡王
一切都很完美的样子
Everything looks perfect
现在要去带珊迪来
We're going to go get Sandy now
干快点  小子
Well, hurry it up, lads
不能一直这样占用蟹堡王
Can't squat like this forever
蟹堡王
Krusty Krab
珊迪的惊喜在蟹堡王
Sandy's surprise is at the Krusty Krab
等到她看到
Wait till she sees the
不要破坏惊喜
Don't spoil the surprise
珊迪
Hey, Sandy
要跟我们一起来蟹堡王吗
You want to come with us to the Krusty Krab?
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
派大星
Hey, Patrick
你大包小包的要干什么
What are you doing with those bags?
我要回德克萨斯老家
I'm goin' back home to Texas
什么
What?
现在吗
Now?
不行
You can't
我们都
I mean, we
该让我这颗风滚草滚回家去了
It's time for this tumbleweed to tumble on home
等等  珊迪
W-Wait, Sandy
你还不能
You can't, uh
因为我们要
'cause we were gonna
蟹堡王那边要
at the Krusty Krab is
那个方向不对
that is not the right direction
别走
Wait
要是你不
If you don't
要是我没法
lf I can't
珊迪  等一下
Sandy, wait a second
你走之前的话
You don't want to leave
最好先到蟹堡王吃个蟹黄堡吧
without having one last Krabby Patty
down at the Krusty Krab
我鱼食吃腻了  海绵宝宝
I'm tired of fish food, SpongeBob
可是珊迪  你就不想
B-But Sandy, don't you want to
到蟹堡王跟你朋友道个别吗
say good-bye to all your friends down at the Krusty Krab?
我做不到  海绵宝宝
I just can't do that, SpongeBob
这样会很伤感
It'd be too sad
不要  别走
N-No, no, wait
珊迪
Sandy
她居然就这么走了
I can't believe she's gone
是啊
Yeah
弱智德克萨斯有什么好的
What's so great about dumb, old Texas?
你说什么
What did you say?
弱智德克萨斯
Texas is dumb?
辱德克萨斯者  后果自负
Don't you dare take the name of Texas in vain
所以不能说弱智德克萨斯的坏话吗
You mean we can't say anything bad about dumb, old Texas?
没错  不能说
No, you can't
那能不能说德克萨斯人弱智
Then, can we say people from Texas are dumb?
不能
No
就是不准说德克萨斯
You can't say nothin' about Texas
所以说我们不能辱  德克萨斯
So we shouldn't say anything bad about Tex-as
我警告你了  海绵宝宝
I'm warning you, SpongeBob
你看  派大星
Look, Patrick
我是德克萨斯
I'm Texas
你们好
Howdy, y'all
我也是德克萨斯
I'm Texas, too
[ 改自民谣"Git Along Little Doggies" ]
快狗吧  小走们
Get a dog, little longie
快狗吧
Howdy, y'all
你们好
快狗吧  小走们
Get a dog, little longie
快狗吧
Get a dog
你们最好给我住嘴
y'all best cut it out
[ 改自民谣"Deep in the Heart of Texas" ]
夜空的星辰黯淡无光
The stars at night are dull and dim
每当它们被迫
Whenever they have to be
照耀在弱智德克萨斯上
Over dumb, old, stupid Texas
派大星  我现在是什么
Hey, Patrick, what am I now?
弱智
Stupid?
错  我是德克萨斯
No, I'm Texas
这有啥区别
What's the difference
你们最好道歉
You all best apologize
否则我就要对你们不客气了
or I'm going to be on you like ugly on an ape
先抓到我们再说
You'll have to catch us first
成了
We did it
她上钩了
We got her
蟹堡王  我们来了
Krusty Krab, here we come
我们能不能说德克萨斯的植物很弱智
Can we say that plants from Texas are dumb?
我们能不能说德克萨斯的鞋子很弱智
Can we say that shoes from Texas are dumb?
派大星  差不多得了
Okay, Patrick, that's enough
得啥啊
Why?
你以为那个慢老婆子德克萨斯会
Do you think that old slowpoke, Texas, is gonna
再跑快点  派大星
Run faster, Patrick
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
给我收回你说的话
You're going to take back what you said
不要
No
快到了
Almost there
蟹堡王
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你这是在惹牛
You been messin' with the bull
现在牛角要过来了
Now here come the horns
不要  珊迪
No, Sandy
不要
No
德克萨斯快乐
你好啊
Howdy, y'all
这
Wha
这是什么
what's this?
是聚会
It's a party
给你办的
For you
给我办的
For me?
这是你专属的一小部分德克萨斯
It's your own little slice of Texas
看一下吧  珊迪
Check it out, Sandy
有方块舞
We got square dancin'
超大烤肉
giant barby-q's
刺 Q
山 核 桃
手工豆罐头派
Homemade peas-in-a-can pies
豆
十    加    仑
还有我们专属的宽边高顶帽
and we got our very own ten-gallon hats
那你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
要留下来吗
You gonna stay?
不要再哭了  珊迪
Don't cry anymore, Sandy
我去帮你拿行李
I'll go get your bags
我没哭
I'm not cryin'
是喜极而泣
I'm laughin'
我很感谢你们做的事  海绵宝宝
I appreciate what y'all are trying to do, SpongeBob
家的真谛并非烤肉还有山核桃派
but home isn't about barbecues and pecan pies
而是在身边
Home is where you're surrounded
有很多关照你的朋友
by other critters that care about you
我这是在干什么
Duh, what am I doin'?
我一直都在家
I been home all along
我到现在才想明白这回事
and I took me till just now to realize it
所以你要留下来吗
Does that mean you'll stay?
我留下来了
I'm stayin'
万岁
Hooray
留下来了
She's stayin'
让我好想摇摆
That makes me feel all wiggly
要弱智德克萨斯干什么
Yeah, who needs dumb, old Texas?
你刚说什么了
What did you just say?
我该开始跑了吗
Should I start running now?
无地自容
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
欢迎来到酷乐湖
海滩游客都听好了
Attention, beachgoers
你们这是非法闯入此地
You are trespassing
你们有十七分钟的时间
You have exactly 17 minutes
挪走你们的死尸  因为这里即将建造
to haul your carcasses off of the future site
海之超级霸
of the Chum Bucket Mega Bucket
超级霸未来选址
听见什么了吗
Do you hear something?
救生员
那行  随你们的便
Okay, have it your way
我就不介意铲平你们所有
I don't mind bulldozing over each and every one
老妈你看
Mommy, look
有人在这放了个玩具卡车
Somebody left this toy tractor here
放下去  比利
Put that down, Billy
上面有细菌
That has germs on it
妈
Mom
等着瞧
You'll see
全都等着瞧
You'll all see
海之超级霸的未来选址
The future site of the Chum Bucket Mega Bucket
可不能被这些白痴海滩游客占走了
must be cleared of these cretinous beachgoers
可事实越来越明显了
but it's becoming increasingly obvious
我再也不能否认了
I can deny it no longer
我太小了
I am small
我需要有个大个的人
I need someone big
帮我清空这片海滩
to clear the beach for me
我需要
I need
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
踏上沙滩
Steppin' on the beach
好啊
Yes
他就是我要找的
He's the one
冰淇淋
我要来一份
I'll have one
来两份
two please
谢谢
Thanks
来一份冰淇淋
One, please
不好意思
Excuse me
来一份冰淇淋
One, please
抱歉  孩子
Sorry, kid
都卖光了
we're all out
真见鬼
Barnacles
痞老板  你在这干什么
Plankton, what are you doing here?
你哭什么啊
And why are you crying?
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
我哭是因为我买了俩冰淇淋甜筒
l'm crying because I've got these two ice cream cones
可我只要一个而已
but I only need one
另外一个不知道要怎么办
I don't know what to do with the other one
我来帮你把其中一个甜筒吃了吧
I'll eat one of those ice cream cones for you
海绵宝宝  你真会帮我吃吗
SpongeBob, would you do that for me?
当然
Sure
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
怎么了
Yeah?
想要的东西到手了感觉不错吧
lsn't it great to get the things you desire?
就比如说刚刚那个甜筒
Like that ice cream cone, for instance
只要稍微再训练一下就能要啥有啥
You can have anything you want with a little training
训练
Training?
没错
Yes
你得学会更加坚定
You just have to learn to be more assertive
我可以教你的
and I can show you how
坚定是吗
Assertive, huh?
没错
That's right
要啥有啥
Anything I want?
真不错
Sounds great
妙极了
Wonderful
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
让他别坐你身上
Don't let that guy sit on you
坚定第一课
Assertiveness lesson number one
叫他下去
Tell him to get off
不好意思  先生
Excuse me, sir
你坐到我身上了
Y-you're sitting on my body
坐的地方也是我的脸
which is also my face
错了  要坚定
No, no, be assertive
[ assert（坚定）与 insert（插入）谐音 ]
不是乱插
Not insertive
海绵宝宝  你错过时机了
SpongeBob, you missed your chance
必须要霸道才能得到想要的东西
You've got to be aggressive to get the things you want
你心太软了
You're too soft
可我是海
But I'm a spong
少废话
Don't say it
是抢走了你冰淇淋的那位
There's the guy who took your ice cream
你不想要回来吗
Don't you want it back?
冰淇淋
Ice cream
你给我听好
Listen, you
我朋友有话要说
My friend's got something to say
什么
What?
谁说的话
Who said that?
是你吗
Was it you?
快骂他  海绵宝宝
Tell him off, SpongeBob
让自己坚定起来
Assert yourself
那是我的冰淇琳甜筒
That's my ice cream cone
不错
Great
让他尝尝厉害
Now let him have it
你尝尝吧
You can have it
谢谢了
Say, thanks
错了
No
我来给你示范
I'll show you how
那个铅笔脖子
Hey, pencil-neck
没错  就你
Yeah, you
给我滑过来
Slither over here
交出那个冰淇淋甜筒
Surrender that ice cream cone
否则你所有清醒的时刻都将化为
or every waking moment for you will become
充斥着痛苦的漩涡
a swirling torrent of pain and misery
他哭了
That guy was crying
他那是喜极而泣
Those were tears of joy
他为你学会了坚定而感到高兴
He was happy that you were assertive
好耶
Yeah
这下知道发起疯来有多美好了吧
You see how wonderful life can be when you're maniacal?
应该是叫坚定吧
I thought it was called assertive
随便
Whatever
要是坚定能让我有这个冰淇淋
Well, if it got me this ice cream
那我喜欢
then I like it
我找到东西了
I found something
不好意思  我金属探测器坏了
Excuse me, my metal detector broke
能借用下你的吗
Can I use yours?
当然
Sure
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
这是你的下一课
This is your next lesson
要霸道
Be aggressive
叫那人滚远点
Tell that guy to take a hike
你要跟我去远足吗
Do you want to take a hike with me?
好啊
Yeah
看你现在干的什么好事
Now look what you've done
叫那人掉沟里去
Tell that guy to go fall in a ditch
到沟里去看看吧
Hey, go check in that ditch
埋藏的宝藏
Wow Buried treasure
谢谢了
Thanks
看见了没  痞老板
Did you see that, Plankton?
那人发现了埋藏的宝藏
That guy found some buried treasure
海绵宝宝  你怎么做都做不好
SpongeBob, you'll never get it right
跟他说你会空手道
Tell that guy you know karate
不还金属探测器就给他绑成结
and you'll tie him in a knot
if you don't get your metal detector back
不还金属探测器  我就给你绑鞋带
I'm going to tie your shoe if you don't give that back
可我穿的是凉鞋
But I'm wearing sandals
好吧
Okay
那没事了
Never mind
没事了  痞老板
It's all right, Plankton
他穿的是凉鞋
He's wearing sandals
有什么问题吗
What's the matter?
没什么  海绵宝宝
Nothing, SpongeBob
妈妈
Mama
我只是开始觉得我这是在浪费时间
I was just beginning
to think that this is a waste of time
你没浪费
No, it's not
算了吧
Forget it
你多半没有顶天立地所需要的素质
I guess you don't have what it takes to be a standup guy
可是飞机餐呢
Well, what about airline food?
什么
What?
飞机餐
Airline food
天啊  这菜怎么搞的那么难吃
My gosh, what is up with that stuff?
谢谢
Thank you
晚安
Good night
顶  天  立  地
看吧  我可以演单口喜剧的
See, I can be a standup guy
懂没
See?
海绵宝宝  你绝对没法要啥有啥
SpongeBob, you'll never get what you want
你老是让别人践踏你
You always let people step all over you
就跟楼梯差不多
You're just like stairs
等等  痞老板
Wait, Plankton
再给我一次机会吧
give me another chance
可以  不过这是你最后一次机会
Okay, but this is your last chance
看那些霸占海滩的人晒着你的阳光
Look at all those beach hogs soaking upyour sun rays
你拥有美黑所需要的素质吗
Do you have what it takes to get a tan?
看我的
Just watch me
天啊  这玩意好多沙子
Man, this thing is sandy
我的腿
My leg
好啊  我的计划开始起效了
Yes, my plan is beginning to work
他们都离开海滩了
They're leaving the beach
海绵宝宝  真是太棒了
SpongeBob, that was wonderful
这是把全身都晒了一遍吗
Is that an all-over tan?
也不算全
Well, not all of me
热狗
Hot dogs
零食吧
热狗
Hot dogs
你看热狗摊前边的那条长队
Look at that huge line at the hot dog stand
坚定起来  插到前边去
Assert yourself to the front
我可以更上一层楼
I'll do better than that
我们回家吧
Let's go home
海绵宝宝  真是太天才了
SpongeBob, that was genius
你看那些放风筝的挡了你视野
Look at all those kite-flyers blocking your view
什么
What?
挡了你的风
Breaking your wind
海绵宝宝  把球扔给我们
Hey, SpongeBob, throw us the ball
现在要咋办
What do we do now?
我看还是回去吧
Let's just go home, I guess
痞老板  你看见了没
Plankton, did you see that?
我是合格的大哥大了
I was a regular alpha male
痞老板
Plankton?
痞老板  我的坚定把大家都赶走了
Plankton, all my asserting has driven everybody away
没错
Exactly
你没跟我说过大家会走的啊
You didn't tell me everyone would leave
超级霸未来选址
超级霸
Mega bucket
你利用我开发土地
You used me for land development
一点都不好
That wasn't nice
还没想明白吗  海绵宝宝
Haven't you figured it out, SpongeBob?
好人没好报
Nice guys finish last
只有霸道的人才能征服世界
Only aggressive people conquer the world
那
Well
霸道的好人会怎么样
what about aggressively nice people?
你在搞什么
What are you doing?
零食吧
关
热狗
Hot dogs
开
等下
Wait
海绵宝宝  住手
SpongeBob, stop
睫毛刷冰淇淋
Butterfly kisses
我
I
受不了
can't take it
太可爱了
It's too cute
太  太恶心了
It's, it's disgusting
怎么了
What happened?
我新冲浪板触礁了  老兄
I hit a reef with my new board, dude
问题不大
No problem
好棒
Killer
海绵宝宝  住手
SpongeBob, stop
现在还来得及
Before it's too late
你的好心好意把大家都带回来了
Your kindness is bringing everybody back
回去
Get back
等等
Wait
不要
No
卡哇邦嘎
Cowabunga
谢了  老兄
Thanks, dude
真是超棒的
That was awesome
痞老板
Gee, Plankton
海之霸的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about the Chum Bucket
别管海之霸了
Forget about that
我只是没办法一口气接受这么多好意
I just can't take so much kindness at one sitting
需要
Need
敌意
hatred
谁想打排球
Volleyball, anyone?
好耶
Yeah
发球
Service
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense is something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants